Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the International Typographical Union PE.004
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the International Typographical Union
1881-1995
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
Schulte, Rebecca
PE.004
3 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons
The Printed Ephemera Collection on the International Typographical Union is an artificial collection, collected and assembled by the staff of the Tamiment Library over the course of several decades. The files contain agreements, contracts and constitutions, as well as printed ephemera such as fliers, leaflets, newspaper clippings, pamphlets and other publications.
Scope and Content Note
The Printed Ephemera Collection on the International Typographical Union consists of constitutions, contracts, agreements, by-laws, memoranda, reports, and printed ephemera such as clippings, flyers, broadsides, leaflets, catalogs, press releases, programs, and pamphlets generated by the national, regional and local bodies, as well as departments and divisions of the union.
One folder added to the collection in 2017 includes newsletters from the International Typographical Union, Women's International Auxiliary.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically with locals and sections after the alphabetical run. Local 6 New York, NY is arranged as a separate series from the main union papers.
Organized into two series: I. International Typographical Union II. Local 6 New York, NY
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library, New York University, a special collection documenting the history of United States radicalism, labor, and progressive social action, accumulated this artificial collection of printed ephemera gradually over the years through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, trade unions and other organizations, and through exchanges with other special library collections via the Collectors' Network, which was organized by Russell Benedict at the University of Nevada in the 1970s and promoted through his newsletter Top Secret. Ongoing collecting by staff is another significant means for acquiring printed ephemera for the collection.
The Library's Trade Union Printed Ephemera Files include material generated by federations and national, regional and local bodies, as well as departments and divisions of trade unions. While a small portion of the material is international in scope or associated with other regions of the United States, the majority of the collection relates to the New York metropolitan area.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with labor unions and other organizations, exchanges with other libraries, and through ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff. There is no accession number associated with these materails.
In 2014 the Spencer Research Library at University of Kansas sent one folder of International Typographical Union and Women's International Auxilary newsletters. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.155.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Typographical Union, Local 6, Benefit Board Records (WAG 119) International Typographical Union, Local 6, Journal of Commerce Chapel (WAG 276)
Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York -- Organizing.; Labor leaders -- New York (State); Strikes and lockouts -- Newspapers -- New York (State) -- New York.; Labor unions -- Printing industry -- New York (State) -- New York.; Pamphlets.; Bylaws (administrative records).; Contracts; Labor unions -- United States.; Newsletters.; Bulletins.; Leaflets (printed works); Fliers (printed matter); Clippings (information artifacts); International Typographical Union; Schulte, Rebecca
- Series I: International Typographical Union, 1881-1995
  - Amalgamation Party, 1935, undated (Box 1)
  - Benefits, 1935-1978 (Box 1)
  - Book and Job Scales, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Elmer, President, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Circular Letters, 1933-1942, undated (Box 1)
  - Clippings and Articles, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Committee for Merger, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1981-1982, 1898 (Box 1)
  - Constitution: Book of Laws, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Constitution: Book of Laws, 1951-1954 (Box 1)
  - Constitution: Book of Laws, 1955, 1957-1959 (Box 1)
  - Constitution: Book of Laws, 1960-1963 (Box 1)
  - Constitution: Book of Laws, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - Constitution: Book of Laws, 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Constitution: Book of Laws, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Constitution: Book of Laws, 1974, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
  - Constitution: Book of Laws, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By-Laws Sample, undated (Box 1)
  - Contract File circular, circa 1960-1970 (Box 1)
  - Conventions, 1950-1980 (Box 1)
  - Directory, Official, 1956, 1958, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Executive Council, 1934-1985 (Box 1)
  - Empire Typographical Conference, 1941, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - History, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Independent Party, 1938-1942 (Box 1)
  - Legislation, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Local 1 (Indianapolis, IN), 1937 (Box 2)
  - Local 2 (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1942 (Box 2)
  - Local 6 (Washington, D.C.): Washington Post, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Local 21 (San Francisco, Ca.), 1955-1958 (Box 2)
  - Local 42 (Minneapolis, MN), 1972 (Box 2)
  - Local 83 (Hebrew American Typographical Union, New York), 1948, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Local 94 (Jersey City, NJ), 1954 (Box 2)
  - Local 174 (Los Angeles, CA), 1953-1955 (Box 2)
  - Local 195 (Patterson, NJ), 1936, 1940, undated (Box 2)
  - Local 896 (Columbia County, NY), undated (Box 2)
  - Local: German-American locals, 1883-1884 (Box 2)
  - National Labor Relations Board, 1949-1960, undated (Box 2)
  - New York Mailers Union Subordinate No. 6, undated (Box 2)
  - New York Newspapers Writers Union No. 4, undated (Box 2)
  - Newsletters, various, 1935-1950 (Box 2)
  - Newsletters, Women's International Auxiliary, 1941-1942, 1984-1991 (Box 2)
  - No. 9 Buffalo NY - Constitution, 1887 (Box 2)
  - No. 9 New York Pressmen's Union, New York, NY, 1887 (Box 2)
  - No 15 Rochester, NY; No. 1735 Knights of Labor, 1885 (Box 2)
  - No. 16 Chicago, IL, 1948 (Box 2)
  - No. 19 Elmira, NY: Constitution and By-Laws, 1885 (Box 2)
  - No. 36 Oakland, CA, undated (Box 2)
  - No. 51 Lawrence, MA, 1989 (Box 2)
  - No. 52 Troy, NY: Constitution and Rules of Order, 1885-1890 (Box 2)
  - No. 58 Portland, OR: Constitution, By-Laws and Scale of Prices, 1885 (Box 2)
  - No. 62 Utica, NY: Constitution and By-Laws, 1885 (Box 2)
  - No. 96 Glen Falls, NY: Constitution, 1885 (Box 2)
  - No. 98 Brooklyn, NY: Constitution and By-Laws, 1885 (Box 2)
  - No. 101 Columbia Typographical Union, 1957 (Box 2)
  - No. 193 Spokane Falls, WA, 1886-1903 (Box 2)
  - No. 202 Seattle, WA, 1901 (Box 2)
  - No. 205 Jamestown, NY: Constitution and By-Laws, 1882 (Box 2)
  - No. 915 Long Island NY: Agreement, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Organizational Manual, circa 1972 (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets and Publications I, 1935-1960s, undated (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets and Publications II, 1953-1980 (Box 2)
  - Pensions, 1939-1979 (Box 2)
  - Philadelphia Inquirer Chapel, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Printing Manuals, 1908-1962 (Box 2)
  - Progressive Party, 1934-1950, undated (Box 2)
  - Proposed Merger with Teamsters: Notice of Referendum, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Report of Officers, 1945-1963 (Box 2)
  - Union Label Promotion, 1934-1942, undated (Box 2)
  - Union Printers Historical Society: Philadelphia Typographical Strikers of 1876, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Union Printers Home, 1919-1934, undated (Box 2)
- Series II: Local 6 New York, NY, 1918-1995
  - Agreements: Publisher's Association of New York, 1956-1960 (Box 2)
  - American Federation of Labor, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Arbitration: Publisher's Association of New York, 1918 (Box 2)
  - Arbitration Proceedings and Findings v. Publisher's Association of New York, 1919 (Box 2)
  - Arbitration Proceedings and Findings v. Employing Printers Association Closed Shop Branch, 1920-1921 (Box 2)
  - Arbitration Proceedings and Findings: Closed Shop Branch New York Employing Printers Association, 1922-1923 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Elmer, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Bulletin, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Circular Letters, 1933-1977, undated (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Columbia Spectator, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Committee of Investigation: Financial Section Report, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1878, 1884-1888 (Box 3)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1954, 1957-1958 (Box 3)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1961-1962, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1968, 1971, 1973, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1991, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Constitutional Revision Committee, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Contracts, 1939, 1944, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Contracts, 1970-1974 (Box 3)
  - Contracts: Book and Job Work, 1887-1889 (Box 3)
  - Contracts: Book and Job Work, 1950-1959 (Box 3)
  - Contracts: Book and Job Work, 1961-1970 (Box 3)
  - Contracts: Book and Job Work, 1970-1975 (Box 3)
  - Directory, 1955 (Box 3)
  - East Coast Regional Conference of Progressives, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Elections; Leadership, 1935-1961 (Box 3)
  - Executive Council, 1936-1961 (Box 3)
  - Herald Chapel Tribune Newsletter, 1939-1942 (Box 3)
  - Independent, The Newsletter, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Legislation, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Members, List of, 1928-1960 (Box 3)
  - Membership, 1930s (Box 3)
  - Meetings of the Unemployed, 1930 (Box 3)
  - New York Times Chapel, 1935-1978, undated (Box 3)
  - New York University Student Paper, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Newsletters, various, 1933-1941 (Box 3)
  - Non-Partisan Committee of Big Six Publications, 1939-1941, undated (Box 3)
  - Powers, Bert, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Progressive Club Newsletter The Progressive, 1935-1959 (Box 3)
  - Scale Conference Committee, circa 1973 (Box 3)
  - Scale of Prices, 1928-1958 (Box 3)
  - Scale of Prices, 1960-1973 (Box 3)
  - Strike, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Strike, 1962-1963 (Box 3)
  - Strike, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Union Label, 1940, undated (Box 3)